[{"id": "5fe7d02d877e98cb97778a5c", "question": "The Catedral de Sal, a cathedral carved entirely out of salt, is located in what country?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f99", "question": "What character from a pop song wears a face that she keeps in a jar by the door?", "answer": "Eleanor Rigby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd535000d154d7af00b8dc", "question": "Which band recorded and released the song\"Cotton Eye Joe\"?", "answer": "Rednex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa6f973838c5c8a417f34", "question": "A crossbreed between a donkey and the zebra is known as what?", "answer": "Zonkey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339386", "question": "What did Francis Coppola call his re-edited version of the movie \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "Apocalypse Now Redux", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f87dfe83fe1f2a824c2e", "question": "In which ancient South Asian language is the text of The Vedas written?", "answer": "Sanskrit - The religious poems originated in northwestern India in 1500-1000 BCE.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a528", "question": "Columbia University is located in which US city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c8d4fbde8045e48466e1", "question": "Why do some plants send chemical signals to bugs?", "answer": "Signal for help -- Leafy tobacco plants send a chemical signal to wasps, who will seek out caterpillars eating the leaves.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ddd1fe83fe1f2a824b64", "question": "Who invented the color wheel?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f67", "question": "What does \"Alma mater\" translate to in English?", "answer": "Bountiful mother", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f72", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the strongest man on Earth?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbfc56ce05a3942286f04", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Caribbean Queen\"?", "answer": "Billy Ocean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd1a", "question": "What bulb vegetable is traditionally worn on Saint David's Day?", "answer": "The leek", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5fb", "question": "Which is the biggest planet in our Solar System?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e47", "question": "What dog is the hero of Jack London's \"The Call of the Wild\"?", "answer": "Buck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78c", "question": "Grits are typically made from what grain?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac58", "question": "What year did World War II end?", "answer": "1945", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d4", "question": "What is the better-known name of the card game \"Twenty-One\"?", "answer": "Blackjack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5c", "question": "In terms of decibels, what is normally the loudest instrument in a symphony orchestra?", "answer": "Trombone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a437", "question": "The geothermal spa \"Blue Lagoon\" is located in what country?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397bb", "question": "What was the first female rap group to win a Grammy in 1995?", "answer": "Salt-N-Pepa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c78", "question": "What artist was best known for his covers of \"The Saturday Evening Post\"?", "answer": "Norman Rockwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c849", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the caudate lobe?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008ee5cf842fa4c4ba96b6", "question": "What were \"Jelly Babies\" renamed to in 1918 to mark the end of World War I?", "answer": "Peace Babies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b056", "question": "What famous magician died on Halloween Day in 1926?", "answer": "Harry Houdini", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1ce957bd84c0ea43ad438", "question": "How many stars are there on the New Zealand flag?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef32ed6ce05a3942286e00", "question": "How many U.S. states are needed to ratify an amendment for it to become part of the constitution?", "answer": "Three-fourths", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc32", "question": "What color is the saffron spice?", "answer": "Yellow-orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b118", "question": "In ancient Japan, all people who gave massages had to be what?", "answer": "Blind", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e8", "question": "When was the tire company, Michelin, founded?", "answer": "1889", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f7", "question": "Who was assassinated at the Lorraine Motel in Memphis,Tennessee?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6e", "question": "Port Said lies on which waterway?", "answer": "The Suez Canal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d1", "question": "Which author built a home called Goldeneye in Jamaica?", "answer": "Ian Fleming", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9dbe2e748bb36357acdd9", "question": "What is the smallest marine mammal?", "answer": "The Sea otter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e91", "question": "What detective novel begins with a dinner hosted by the mysteriously absent \"Mr. U. N. Owen\"?", "answer": "And Then There Were None", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbd", "question": "Which University was founded as the College of New Jersey?", "answer": "Princeton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b27", "question": "Who is credited with writing the first detective story, \"The Murders in the Rue Morgue\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f70bba9e54d890926f6d7", "question": "In which city is the majority of the Las Vegas Strip located?", "answer": "Paradise -- The majority of the 4.2-mile stretch of glittering lights is actually located in the neighboring town of Paradise.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067c9dff9c0647b50a806d", "question": "What virtual reality set was launched in March, 2016?", "answer": "Occulus Rift", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe000ae1cf6db9ac4808d15", "question": "Which country has the oldest airport in the world that's still in operation?", "answer": "USA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c8", "question": "What year did Pinocchio first appear in published media?", "answer": "1883", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a3", "question": "What stars of the movie \"Eyes Wide Shut\" divorced shortly after the film was made?", "answer": "Tom Cruise and Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c1", "question": "What world leader sold the Louisiana Territory to the US?", "answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f84", "question": "The Michael Douglas film \"A Perfect Murder\" is a remake of what 1950s thriller?", "answer": "Dial M for Murder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e6", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Bart of Darkness,\" what does Bart break?", "answer": "His leg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891f", "question": "What is the name of the dragon in \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Smaug", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e8a8745404ad935a7e1a63d", "question": "According to the commercial, how many licks does it take to get to the center of a tootsie pop?", "answer": "Three - A one a two a three *crunch*", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaa287e83c707845b20dc", "question": "What does the ozone layer protect the Earth against?", "answer": "Ultraviolet light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99f", "question": "What phenomenon is caused by the gravitational attraction of the Earth's moon?", "answer": "Tides", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015fcaefe83fe1f2a824c43", "question": "At the age of 16, Saint Patrick was kidnapped by pirates. What work did his captors force him to do?", "answer": "They made him tend and rear animals", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb5c795dad637d903c881e", "question": "\"Ital\" is the word used to describe the cuisine of which group of people?", "answer": "Rastafarians", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bc", "question": "U2's David Evans is better known by which nickname?", "answer": "The Edge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae33", "question": "When did the War of 1812 actually begin?", "answer": "1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfd749dc5ec6cd98a8324", "question": "What famous literary character offers this sage advice: \"Neither a borrower nor a lender be\"?", "answer": "Polonius (In\u00a0\"Hamlet\"\u00a0(Act I, Scene III),\u00a0he offers the sage advice to his son Laertes who is about to leave home.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fe", "question": "In what country was Adolf Hitler born?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fb", "question": "Where is the opening scene of the movie \"Love Actually\" shot?", "answer": "An airport", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59524476736d4be723796b69", "question": "What city did Lando Calrissian live in in \"Star Wars V: The Empire Strikes Back\"?", "answer": "Cloud City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65bfb1f3c0ead6880d60b", "question": "According to the Bible, where was Apollos from?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1f", "question": "In golf, what is the traditional name for a number 3 wood?", "answer": "Spoon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a1", "question": "What US road sign is typically shaped like a triangle?", "answer": "Yield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c1b7877e98cb9777897b", "question": "What Roman building is known as the \"Square Colosseum\"?", "answer": "Palazzo della Civilt\u00e0 Italiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9a", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, what is the value of the letters \"Q\" and \"Z\"?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad08", "question": "What H-word means designing, displaying and describing coats of arms and badges?", "answer": "Heraldry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e9a6cebfabb9c85d8a97b", "question": "What type of food is \"Limburger\"?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d3", "question": "What liquor is nicknamed \"the green fairy\"?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399db", "question": "What 2005 Gwen Stefani song was the first single to amass one million paid digital downloads?", "answer": "Hollaback Girl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ea16b24f84e0b9f9ffcf", "question": "What group sang the theme song to the TV show \"Square Pegs\"?", "answer": "The Waitresses", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0b", "question": "Who recorded the 1983 Top 5 hit \"She Works Hard for the Money\"?", "answer": "Donna Summer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133965f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which character is allergic to regular milk?", "answer": "Milhouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea380fff048f679a45ab20", "question": "What is the scientific name for the job or role an organism plays in its habitat?", "answer": "Niche", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8afb901dd7bf43be5e78a", "question": "What is the term for a word that is spelled the same forwards and backwards?", "answer": "Palindrome", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded2ebea2747c8aff16d43", "question": "What is a device to stem the flow of blood called?", "answer": "A tourniquet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9bb13364247bf200fb89f", "question": "Which album did the Bee Gees release in 1971?", "answer": "Trafalgar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a09", "question": "Who played the first \"Tool Time Girl\" on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3d", "question": "Which archaeologist discovered King Tut's tomb in 1922?", "answer": "Howard Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae862f37f28483af1e7fdc8", "question": "What country did Hawaiian pizza come from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf7b", "question": "What nationality was the architect Le Corbusier?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccbabec223966ae8f889e", "question": "When Jackie Chan's foot catches on fire in \"The Legend of Drunken Master\", how does he put it out?", "answer": "Kicks water that's thrown on the set", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be57", "question": "What do Americans commonly call Emmental cheese?", "answer": "Swiss cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339605", "question": "What name is given to the virus in the 2002 movie \"28 Days Later\"?", "answer": "The Rage Virus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa58973838c5c8a417f26", "question": "What insects are sometimes called devil\u2019s darning needles?", "answer": "Dragonfly (They\u2019ve also been called darners and devil\u2019s arrows.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba25", "question": "Which sport is played for the Corbillon cup?", "answer": "Table Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339862", "question": "In Disney's Pinocchio, what colour is the fairy who gives life to Pinocchio?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdffbdb668d7dfe168b5bb", "question": "This ancient attempt to transmute base metals into noble metals was called what?", "answer": "Alchemy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6dc", "question": "What do sumo wrestlers call their hair topknots?", "answer": "Chonmage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bb4cd96d05b23b28164c", "question": "Which President was the first to officially recognize Hanukkah?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3d", "question": "Where is the city of Tobruk located?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80f", "question": "What two snacks are mentioned in \"Take Me Out to the Ballgame\"?", "answer": "Peanuts and Cracker Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7eb1bb24f84e0b9f9ffdb", "question": "What fell into the pool in the film \"Caddyshack\" which caused a major exodus?", "answer": "A Baby Ruth candy bar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339853", "question": "In \"Spirited Away\", Yubabas giant baby Boh gets turned into what?", "answer": "Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac94", "question": "Which Soviet leader approved the building of the Berlin Wall?", "answer": "Nikita Khrushchev", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e2", "question": "Who is the director of the movie \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ec0e08d98002fdd633b6", "question": "Which singer wrote the autobiography \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be5816b5415ba52ed6f0ac1", "question": "What is the study of pronunciation called?", "answer": "Orthoepy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa12", "question": "What city is Sugarloaf Mountain located in?", "answer": "Rio de Janeiro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29a", "question": "What planet has the shortest year?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc3fc6ce05a3942286f2a", "question": "What pop duo recorded \"Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)\"?", "answer": "Eurythmics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984e", "question": "What is the name of the villain from the movie \"Mulan\"?", "answer": "Shan Yu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65551ae7e414034b5aeaf", "question": "Greek Mythology, who was responsible for the abduction of Persephone which led to the four seasons of the Earth?", "answer": "Hades", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbe", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in a rickey?", "answer": "Limes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59decf2fea2747c8aff16d1b", "question": "What is sometimes referred to as Zulu time?", "answer": "Greenwich Mean Time", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35e", "question": "Where is the International Court of Justice?", "answer": "The Hague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff13fa4b0ee8c595b6d3990", "question": "How long did it take Michelangelo to paint the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "4 years", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b1cc01dd7bf43be5e795", "question": "What is someone who is \"making a mountain out of a molehill\" doing?", "answer": "Exaggerating a minor problem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca15", "question": "What does a dipsomaniac crave?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be33", "question": "How many players are there in a standard American football team?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff13fb0b0ee8c595b6d3991", "question": "What famous author was known for his love of cats with extra toes?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded01fea2747c8aff16d23", "question": "In which sport is the America's Cup awarded?", "answer": "Sailboat racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59db751e0ab2c8f322317fe4", "question": "Peridot is the birthstone for which month?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb2dc65ff7d326b622a7a", "question": "Which Apollo space mission put the first men on the moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde5297c6c6b019850c9a97", "question": "What was the motto of the Hitler Youth in World War II?", "answer": "Blood and Honor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0d", "question": "What is the capital of Comoros?", "answer": "Moroni", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c453", "question": "What part of the cinnamon tree becomes the spice?", "answer": "The bark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600241204be4723ccac22170", "question": "What Italian sculptor/architect is credited with creating the Baroque style?", "answer": "Gian Lorenzo Bernini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca63", "question": "What ore is the primary source of Aluminium?", "answer": "Bauxite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a1a2ff12f2a7826b9b8721", "question": "What French designer introduced the sack dress in the 1950's?", "answer": "Christian Dior", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e79", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"Love and Marriage\" by Frank Sinatra as its theme song?", "answer": "Married...with Children", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988a", "question": "What instrument is Questlove most famous for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca7", "question": "The adjective \"callipygian\" refers to someone who has a beautiful what?", "answer": "Butt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cbffa6de0eb824d4052d6", "question": "Where is the world's largest greenhouse?", "answer": "Cornwall, England -- The Eden Project is home to more than one million plants. It features two hexagonally-patterned biomes.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b99", "question": "Who is the main character in the Odyssey?", "answer": "Odysseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3d1fff048f679a45ab48", "question": "A medical condition that has been caused by a physician or medical treatment is described as what?", "answer": "Iatrogenic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae11", "question": "Who was Henry VIII's first wife?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c3094f032c0db195b489", "question": "Who was the first European to discover New Zealand?", "answer": "Abel Janszoon Tasman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1af", "question": "Construction of the Colosseum finished under the ruling of which emperor?", "answer": "Titus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b674", "question": "What airport did the first commercial Boeing 747 flight from JFK land at?", "answer": "London, Heathrow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a1", "question": "Which country hosted the first Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be55", "question": "Who plays their home games in the so-called Dean Dome?", "answer": "The North Carolina Tar Heels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb68", "question": "What pharmaceutical company manufactures the drug Viagra?", "answer": "Pfizer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00d", "question": "The Titanic sank while on its way to what city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339255", "question": "What drink does William spill on Anna the second time they meet in the movie \"Notting Hill\"?", "answer": "Orange Juice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7dd", "question": "Which Canadian provinces are known as the \"Maritime Provinces\"?", "answer": "New Brunswick, Nova Scotia and Prince Edward Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f33d01dd7bf43be5e816", "question": "In the US, what does AARP stand for?", "answer": "American Association of Retired Persons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b121", "question": "In what decade did Dr. Christiaan Barnard perform the first successful human heart transplant?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05d", "question": "What is the name of the genetically modified dinosaur in the 2015 movie \"Jurassic World\"?", "answer": "Indominus Rex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d28", "question": "What children's books character is friends with Christopher Robin?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22a", "question": "The fear of punishment is known as what?", "answer": "Poinephobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd4bc600d154d7af00b8ce", "question": "Which nu metal band released the songs \"My Way\" and \"Rollin'\"?", "answer": "Limp Bizkit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936c", "question": "Who was originally cast as Marty in the movie \"Back To The Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stoltz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d117d04fea7fe947a2227d", "question": "Which German firm produced the World War II plane known as the Condor?", "answer": "Focke-Wulf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3cd", "question": "What is added to white sugar to make brown sugar?", "answer": "molasses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec87cfec223966ae8f8818", "question": "Which 1980's NBA player set the record for most assists by a player during his rookie season?", "answer": "Mark Jackson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000f1379a72b906b34e3d02", "question": "What is the largest constellation in the sky?", "answer": "Hydra -- Hydra covers about 1,303 square degrees, which is equal to roughly 3% of the entire celestial sphere.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008fc3cf842fa4c4ba96c0", "question": "Who wrote the epic poem \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b4", "question": "What fruit is normally squeezed into a margarita?", "answer": "Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c1", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Wolverine State\"?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34a", "question": "Which country was the setting for the TV serial \"The Flame Trees of Thika\"?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a797", "question": "Havana is located on which side of Cuba?", "answer": "The west", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c245", "question": "What is Fahrenheit equivalent of 100 degrees centigrade?", "answer": "212 degrees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab144ebaab681b09292172", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937eea308d98002fdd633d6", "question": "\"Confide in Me\" was a hit in 1994 for which singer?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbe446ce05a3942286eeb", "question": "In the film \"Red Dragon,\" Hannibal Lector speculates Will Graham is wearing what brand of shaving lotion?", "answer": "Old Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c22", "question": "What is the 1st line of the chorus of the \"Beer Barrel Polka\"?", "answer": "Roll out the Barrel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600a274ee958e8c9f3127314", "question": "Who is the city of Regina, Saskatchewan named for?", "answer": "Queen Victoria - Originally a hunters\u2019 camp named Pile O\u2019Bones, the settlement was renamed Regina, Latin for \"queen\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62b", "question": "What river flows along the southern border of South Carolina?", "answer": "Savannah River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b341", "question": "John Augustus Larson invented what in 1921?", "answer": "Lie detector (Polygraph)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae69", "question": "What did Ronald Reagan disclose he was suffering from in 1994?", "answer": "Alzheimer's Disease", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a2", "question": "What was the longest-running musical on Broadway during the 20th century?", "answer": "Cats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab43", "question": "Vienna is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f34dcee580c7f8fd1e55", "question": "Who said, \"I ain't got time to bleed.\"?", "answer": "Jesse Ventura", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339801", "question": "What looks like a saxophone but sounds like a harmonica?", "answer": "Goofus or Couesnophone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399da", "question": "What 1990 hit song by Jane's Addiction begins with the sound of dogs barking?", "answer": "Been Caught Stealing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8c", "question": "Which of the 7 dwarves did not speak?", "answer": "Dopey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f9", "question": "For whom is Hadassah, the Jewish women's organization, named?", "answer": "Esther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb085dacf631c2414a13b4f", "question": "In the TV show \"Friends\", what is Chandler\u2019s middle name?", "answer": "Muriel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f164c83f9b80650dbe7f92f", "question": "Who plays Thor in the 2017 film \"Thor: Ragnarok\"?", "answer": "Chris Hemsworth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa59773838c5c8a417f27", "question": "Ambergris is a waxy substance that originates as a secretion from what animal?", "answer": "Sperm whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb5", "question": "Which British dandy introduced long trousers as conventional wear for men?", "answer": "Beau Brummell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a87", "question": "In \"Minority Report\", what part of Tom Cruise's anatomy does his character replace to help him avoid authorities?", "answer": "His eyes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eec", "question": "Actor Jim Caviezel was struck by lightning during the filming of what movie?", "answer": "The Passion of the Christ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e4", "question": "In what country was the \"Michelin Guide\" first published in 1900?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd18b3629d03ab85b632b2f", "question": "What is a female turkey called?", "answer": "Hen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d077ab870e6f05ba600866", "question": "Which private eye character did the author Raymond Chandler create?", "answer": "Philip Marlowe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b36f751c3f17ccc40c8e0e", "question": "In the film \"The Sixth Sense\", what does Cole find in the box Kyra directed him to?", "answer": "A videotape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9e", "question": "What Ray Charles song was the basis for Kanye West's \"Gold Digger\"?", "answer": "I Got a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf8", "question": "What rubber Wham-O toy inspired the name of one of the world's largest sporting events?", "answer": "The Super Bowl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b716", "question": "What is the Christmas dinner of choice for families in Burgundy, France?", "answer": "Turkey and chestnuts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339734", "question": "How many frames fit into 1 foot of movie film?", "answer": "16", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd4", "question": "What is the minimum Scoville rating for a Scotch Bonnet pepper?", "answer": "Around 150,000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b9", "question": "What comedic duo starred in the movie \"Stir Crazy\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder and Richard Pryor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d7", "question": "Which actor played the role of God in the movie \"Bruce Almighty\"?", "answer": "Morgan Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b508", "question": "What popular board game involving money was banned in the Soviet Union?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339726", "question": "How many fingers does Mickey Mouse have?", "answer": "8", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba37d874c93a3298b213c", "question": "What additional part does someone with Polyorhidism have?", "answer": "Extra testicle(s)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b4", "question": "What movie contains the line: \"Hold me like you did by the lake on Naboo\"?", "answer": "Star Wars Episode III: Revenge of the Sith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339395", "question": "Which actor from the cast of the movie \"Rain Man\" won an Oscar?", "answer": "Dustin Hoffmann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0a", "question": "If you have singultus, what do you suffer from?", "answer": "Hiccups", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76f0aeec85e375820b2e2", "question": "Which country has the longest town name?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "593c4c98b8198b9a2b07796a", "question": "In which city does Spider-Man live and protect?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c16", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the fourth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Flies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339135", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Hamlet\", who is the daughter of Polonius?", "answer": "Ophelia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fad", "question": "In ballet, a lowering of the body by bending the knee is called a what?", "answer": "Fondu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa61c73838c5c8a417f2d", "question": "What is the process by which a Komodo Dragon can reproduce asexually?", "answer": "Parthenogenesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8ad3101dd7bf43be5e777", "question": "Who invented the color wheel?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab64", "question": "From what country did the US buy the Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe698dc20565ad31a57c73c", "question": "What singers lure sailors to crash on the rocks with their songs?", "answer": "Sirens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f71", "question": "Which musical was based on H. G. Wells novel \"Kipps: The Story of a Simple Soul\"?", "answer": "Half a Sixpence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5af", "question": "How many bytes are there in a kilobyte?", "answer": "1024", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35c", "question": "Where is Lake Como?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3c", "question": "What type of musical instrument is crafted with two parallel pipes, one known as a chanter and the other a drone?", "answer": "The bagpipe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca28", "question": "What is the name of the instrument used for listening to the heart?", "answer": "Stethoscope\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b333", "question": "What was founded in the UK in 1694 because of war with France?", "answer": "Bank of England", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d2942596a59cbdfbd390", "question": "Who has won the most Oscars?", "answer": "Katherine Hepburn (4)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb64765ff7d326b622a95", "question": "What animal lives in a holt or couch?", "answer": "An otter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60077f91bd51d85e222ab63d", "question": "What school of art grew out of the poetry of Romanian-born Tristan Tzara?", "answer": "The\u00a0Dada\u00a0school of art, or Dadaism was born out of the widespread disillusionment created by World War I.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bd05b4540191c55fd523fb1", "question": "Which person is most often associated with SpaceX and Tesla?", "answer": "Elon Musk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a5", "question": "Which Flintstones character was absent from the Flintstone vitamins until 1996?", "answer": "Betty Rubble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e7ec06d333868d34d745", "question": "Who did Mao Zedong lead in the \"Long March\" in 1934-35?", "answer": "Chinese Red Army", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338957", "question": "What is by far the most famous painting in the Louvre?", "answer": "The Mona Lisa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4bba49076251badbeac7", "question": "How many rooms are there in Buckingham Palace (total number)?", "answer": "775 -- It includes 19 State rooms, 92 offices, 52 Royal and guest bedrooms, 188 bedrooms for staff and 78 bathrooms.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc4046de0eb824d4052f0", "question": "In what state is it a law for apple pie to be served with cheese?", "answer": "Vermont -- According to a 1999 law, apple pie must be served with a least one once of cheddar cheese, ice cream or milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338999", "question": "The story of Samson appears in which book of the Old Testament?", "answer": "Judges", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596dfa93cf3977a46e7ce447", "question": "The Statue of Liberty was a gift resulting from the diplomatic relationship between the United States and what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caea", "question": "What invention is Arthur W. Savage often linked with?", "answer": "The radial tire", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e4", "question": "What was Higgins first name in the TV show \"Magnum PI\"?", "answer": "Jonathan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b337", "question": "Who rode Shergar to victory in the Epsom Derby?", "answer": "Walter Swinburn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb77", "question": "What is the name for the type of scissors which produce a zig-zag cut when cutting fabric?", "answer": "Pinking shears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de0", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"safari\"?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c87", "question": "Who has the only speaking part in Mel Brooks' \"Silent Movie\"?", "answer": "Marcel Marceau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a6dd20565ad31a57c7e0", "question": "Who was the founding commandant of the Nazi concentration camp Auschwitz?", "answer": "Rudolph H\u00f6ss", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960e", "question": "What actor played Royal Tenenbaum?", "answer": "Gene Hackman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b663", "question": "Which automaker sold a car model named \"Colt\"?", "answer": "Dodge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339929", "question": "What musical, set in New York City, won 10 Academy Awards?", "answer": "West Side Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950f", "question": "Who voiced the character Atta in the movie \"A Bug's Life\"?", "answer": "Julia Louis Dreyfuss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60172d4c44491cbd7c5a177f", "question": "What general commanded the American Expeditionary Forces on the Western Front during World War I?", "answer": "John Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing GCB", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede5b66ce05a3942286def", "question": "Which American television sitcom is about a witch who marries an ordinary man and lives as a suburban housewife?", "answer": "\"Bewitched\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e2", "question": "Which US state is closest to Cuba?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c8", "question": "Which TV character owns a talking cat called Salem?", "answer": "Sabrina Spellman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a80", "question": "Who wrote the novel Oryx and Crake?", "answer": "Margaret Atwood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a5", "question": "How many liters is 1 quart?", "answer": "0.946 L", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339751", "question": "What TV show starred Frankie Muniz playing the role of Malcolm?", "answer": "Malcolm in the Middle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b2", "question": "What animal guards the cave of Caerbannog in \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\"?", "answer": "Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db9", "question": "How does the hook-handed Woody Harrelson lose his right hand in the film \"Kingpin\"?", "answer": "In a bowling ball return", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded21eea2747c8aff16d3a", "question": "Which 19th century French artist painted \"Bathers at Asnieres\"?", "answer": "Georges Seurat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971d", "question": "Sandra Bullock won the 2009 Best Actress Oscar for her role in which movie?", "answer": "The Blind Side", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec89cfec223966ae8f882a", "question": "In which 2000 movie did George Clooney play Captain Billy Tyne?", "answer": "\"A Perfect Storm\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abfa", "question": "In which continent would you find the Volga River?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c779", "question": "What aquatic reptile can hold its breath under water for up to 15 minutes?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049b29cf93664eb104869d", "question": "Alan Moore co-created which antihero that first appeared in an 1985 issue of \"The Saga of the Swamp Thing\"?", "answer": "John Constantine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef96166ce05a3942286e9a", "question": "In what Disney movie would you find the character of Briar Rose?", "answer": "\"Sleeping Beauty\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7f", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Asian player to be named Rookie of the Year in Major League Baseball?", "answer": "Hideo Nomo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8ac5601dd7bf43be5e76a", "question": "Which type of fruit juice did Dole sell first?", "answer": "Pineapple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1cd977bd84c0ea43ad42a", "question": "Which country borders Macedonia to the east?", "answer": "Bulgaria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd82396d0de9af39e9d46b0", "question": "The first female U.S. senator was from what state?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7ccd3877e98cb97778a2c", "question": "Which country formerly ruled Iceland?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1997baab681b09292192", "question": "What year was NASCAR founded?", "answer": "1948", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad9", "question": "What Grand Slam sports event is held at Flushing Meadows, NY?", "answer": "US Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a92", "question": "What was Clarence Rutherford\u2019s nickname on the TV show \"Leave it to Beaver\"?", "answer": "Lumpy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c90", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Sunnydale, California?", "answer": "Buffy the Vampire Slayer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf06", "question": "What is the study of bells called?", "answer": "Campanologist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fe", "question": "How many episodes of \"The X-Files\" were made?", "answer": "202", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a160", "question": "When did Sid Vicious join the Sex Pistols?", "answer": "1977", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2e", "question": "What drug is everyone encouraged to take in the novel \"A Brave New World\"?", "answer": "Soma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5da856251aec824685d88d05", "question": "What continent is Morocco located in?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69a4c20565ad31a57c752", "question": "Plato thought the Lost Island of Atlantis was linked to which ancient culture?", "answer": "Minoan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a291", "question": "Who became Yusuf Islam in 1977?", "answer": "Cat Stevens", "category": "entertainment"}]